Gunnar Inge Gjøvik Sortland

Address: Byåsveien 142D, 7021 Trondheim

PHONE: 90 65 80 23

EMAIL: gunnaringe@gmail.com

Birth: 23. april 1985

ABOUT ME

Gunnar Inge obtained a Master's Degree (Master of Science / Sivilingeniør) during the sprint of 2012 at the Norwegian University of Science and Technology within Computer Science specializing in algorithm and hardware design.

For his thesis he won the FPGA Forum's prize of best master's thesis within the field of FPGAs. FPGAs are integrated circuits which contains programmable logic, such that this can be used instead of printet circuits in tests or areas where there is a need for high performance and specialized hardware.

During this thesis he developed a fully functional heterogenous multicore architecture processor with a shared memory interface running on an FPGA. To aid development on this architecture a syncronization library was written in C.

For his specialization project he evaluated different Task Based Parallelism frameworks, such as OpenMP, Intel Cilk Plus and Wool. The heterogenous multicore architecture developed during the master's thesis are ment to be expanded into supporting these kind of frameworks.

He is also certified within both frontend development with HTML5+JavaScript (Programming in HTML5 With JavaScript and CSS3 Specialist) and backend using Java (Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer) og C# (Programming in C# Specialist).

He is fond of programming and problem solving, and have good collaboration skills. He enjoys working both independently and in a team. He likes to learn, and is a fast learner. Gunnar Inge is concerned that the work that is being done is of good quality and works structured towards that goal.

EDUCATION

08.2007 – 06.2012	Master of Science i Computer Science, NTNU , Trondheim
08.2004 – 06.2010	Bachelor i Samfunnsøkonomi, NTNU , Trondheim
08.2001 – 06.2004	Kristelig Videregående Trøndelag, Trondheim
	Specialization in economy and administration, 3FY, 3MX, 2KJ

Work experience

08.2012-P.T.	Capgemini Norge AS
	Consultant
06.2011 – 08.2011	Yahoo! Technologies Norway
	Summer job
01.2011 – 06.2011	Yahoo! Technologies Norway
	Part time
08.2010 12.2010	Yahoo! Technologies Norway
	Part time
06.2010 – 08.2010	Yahoo! Technologies Norway
	Summer job
2005 – 2010	Kulinarium AS
	Waiter and chef assistant
08.2009 – 12.2009	IDI, NTNU
	Student assistant TDT4102 – Procedural and Object-Oriented Programming
08.2009 - 12.2009	IDI, NTNU
	Undervisningsassistent TDT4105/TDT4110 – IT Grunnkurs
01.2009 – 06.2009	IDI, NTNU
	Studentassistent IT1102 – IT Grunnkurs
08.2008 12.2008	IDI, NTNU
	Studentassistent TDT4105 – IT Grunnkurs

PROJECTS

03.2013-р.т.

Statoil

The Endur Integration Services-team are responsible for all integrations towards Endur in Statoil, used within gas production and trade. As this is business critical system system, where errors may have severe economical implications, these system have strict requirements with regard to guaranteed deliveries of messages and monitoring.

As a part of this team, Gunnar Inge have developed new integration modules, introduced unit testing of modules and other required tasks.

02.2013 - 03.2013

Lydia

Lydia delivers a comprehensive Facilities Management System, where the system's users can administer all the information needed to manage a larger building mass.

We developed support for creating reports for rental agreements, with support for area hatching for usage of the floor plan. The system is developed in .NET 4.0, with use of WPF and Infragistics. This system integrated an existing solution for converting floorplans from AutoCAD format to XAML.

09.2012 - 12.2012

Verdande Technology

Verdande Technology AS was established in 2004 by a group of professors and students from NTNU in Trondheim. They are leading in development of specialized Case Based Reasoning (CBR) systems, delivering software solution for collecting historical data and events. Using this historical data they can extract knowledge which can be used to predict future events and possibly avoid unwanted ones.

We developed an test client in Java for stress testing an existing real time solution running on the Amazon Elastic Compute Cload (Amazon EC2). The test clients are simulating a typical user session, with configured user behavior.

Volunteer duties

09.2011-09.2012 | SØR TRØNDELAG KRFU

2. deputy chairman

08.2011-05.2013 | NTNUI TENSHI-TSUME

Member of board and webadmin (martial arts group)

02.2010-01.2011 Trondheim Sentrum KrF

Chairman

11-2008-03.2009 | ISFiT - Student Peace Price

Part of the work group of the Student Peace Price

2007–2008 | Sameiet Brøsetvegen 186

Chairman

2006–2007 | Studenttinget NTNU

Studenttings representant

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java Good command

C# Good command

C/C++ Good command

PYTHON Good command

JAVASCRIPT Good command

VHDL Used for master's thesis

Ruby Some knowledge

Prolog Some knowledge

Oz Some knowledge

Assembly Some knowledge